www.tvsubtitles.net
Cersei:
What are you doing here?
Varys: Your father has named
Lord Tyrion
to serve as Hand
in his stead.
- You brought this on yourself.
- I've done nothing.
Do you understand
we're losing the war?
Does it ever end?
Jorah: Everything ends,
even the Red Waste.
( Daenerys
speaking Dothraki )
Dolorus Edd: All the other wildlings
for 100 leagues
have disappeared.
Craster's still here.
Any man lays a hand on one
of my wives, he loses the hand.
Dolorus Edd:
He marries his daughters
and they give him
more daughters.
What happens to the boys?
What does he do with his sons?
Matthos: "My brother Robert
left no trueborn heirs,
the boy Joffrey
being born of incest
between Cersei Lannister
and her brother Jaime Lannister.
By right of birth
and blood,
I do this day lay claim to the
Iron Throne of Westeros."
Send copies of that letter
to every corner of the realm.
Robb: I'm sending one of
your cousins down to King's
Landing with my peace terms.
You think my father's going
to negotiate with you?
You don't know him
very well.
We won't beat them until
you take King's Landing.
And we can't take
King's Landing without ships.
My father has ships
and men who know how to sail.
Men who fought
my father.
I'm his only living son.
He'll listen to me.
You don't want
Balon Greyjoy for an ally.
- I need his ships.
- He is not trustworthy.
I heard a disgusting lie
about Uncle Jaime and you.
- Father had other children.
- What are you asking?
Joffrey: How many bastards does
he have running around?
( Screaming )
Where is the bastard?
The Night's Watch!
Heading north!
( Theme music playing )
♪ Game of Thrones 2x02 ♪
The Night Lands
Original Air Date on April 8, 2012
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♪
( Urinating )
( Birds chittering )
- ( Rustling )
- ( Urinating stops )
- ( Men chattering )
- ( Horse neighs )
Man: Gotta be ready
before nightfall.
Man #2:
Okay, keep moving.
Man: Put a watch
on the Ridge
and the tree lines.
Man #3: Boy.
Lovely boy.
What do you want?
A man has a thirst.
A man does not drink
for a day and a night.
A boy could
make a friend.
- I have friends.
- ( Clangs )
Give us beer
before I skin you.
A man does not choose
his companions.
These two, they have
no courtesy.
A man must ask
forgiveness.
You're called Arry?
This man has the honor
to be Jaqen H'ghar,
once of the free city of--
Beer, you little shit.
Get us beer!
You should have
asked nicely.
Aah!
Come closer
and I'll shove that stick
up your bunghole
and fuck you bloody.
A boy has more courage
than sense.
Come here!
Yoren said none of us
were to go near those three.
- Come here!
- They don't scare me.
Hmm?
Then you're stupid.
They scare me.
( Horse neighs )
What are Gold Cloaks doing so
far from King's Landing?
- What are you doing?
- They're looking for me.
You in command here?
You're a long way
from home.
I asked you a question.
Aye, you did.
You asked
without manners
and I chose not to answer.
I have a royal warrant
for one of these gutter rats
you're transporting.
Well, the thing is...
These gutter rats belong
to the Night's Watch.
Now, that puts them beyond the
reach of Kings and Queens.
Does it?
It's a funny thing--
people worry so much
about their throats
that they forget
about what's down low.
Now I sharpened this blade
before breakfast.
I could shave a spider's arse
if I wanted to
or I could nick
this artery in your leg.
And once it's nicked,
there's no one around here
who knows
how to unnick it.
We'll just keep that.
Good steel is always
needed on the Wall.
Seems you have
a choice--
you can die here at this crossroads
a long way from home,
or you can go back to your city
and tell your Masters
you didn't find
what you were looking for.
We're looking
for a boy named Gendry.
He carries
a bull's head helmet.
Anyone turning him over
will earn the King's reward.
We'll be back
with more men
and I'll be taking your head
home along with that bastard boy.
( Horse neighs )
( Men murmuring )
- ( Whistling )
- ( Distant seagulls screeching )
( Bells pealing )
- ( Whistling ) ( Distant seagulls
( Shae laughing )
My Lord.
You make me wait
a long time,
but your friend
keeps me company.
We were just speaking
of your bravery
in the victory against
the Stark auxiliary forces.
It was quite a battle.
I heard you suffered
a terrible head wound.
The northerners
are such fearsome warriors.
And I tell him
the story of how we meet.
To find so lovely
a creature
working in your
father's kitchens--
it almost beggars belief.
Strange things do happen.
You should taste
her fish pie.
I don't think Lord Varys
likes fish pie.
- How can you tell?
- I can always tell.
Tyrion: Men like Lord Varys
and I can't let
our disadvantages
get the best of us.
We'll make a fisherman
of him yet.
I am glad
your new friend
was able to accompany you
to the capital.
Friends are such
an important part of life.
Unfortunate that your father
didn't want her to come.
But rest easy, My Lord.
I am very good
at keeping secrets
for my good friends.
Your discretion
is legendary...
where your friends
are concerned.
How unspeakable of me
to go on and on
when all you want
to do is rest.
I will leave you.
Welcome to King's Landing,
my dear.
This city is made brighter
by your presence.
We have a council meeting,
My Lord.
I don't like threats.
- Who threatened you?
- I'm not Ned Stark.
I understand the way
this game is played.
Ned Stark
was a man of honor.
And I am not.
Threaten me again and I'll have
you thrown into the sea.
You might be disappointed
in the results.
Storms come and go,
the big fish eat
the little fish,
and I keep on paddling.
Come, My Lord.
We shouldn't keep
the queen waiting.
Cersei: "From this time
until the end of time,
we are not part
of your realm,
but a free and independent
kingdom of the North."
He has more spirit than
his father, I'll give him that.
You've perfected the art
of tearing up papers.
We can give him his father's bones
back at least
as a gesture
of good faith.
You'll give the Starks
our reply, cousin?
I will, Your Grace.
Did you see my brother
when you were
the Starks' guest?
Alton:
I did.
They have not broken
his spirit, Your Grace.
If you speak with him,
tell him he's not
been forgotten.
- Alton: I will, Your Grace.
- Safe travels, cousin.
You have a deft hand
with diplomacy.
- If that's everything...
- A-- a raven flew in this morning
from Castle Black.
Trouble with
the wildlings.
That's why they're
called "wildlings."
Somewhat less wild
these days.
Seems they've stopped
killing each other
and started following
this King-Beyond-the-Wall.
Another king?
How many is that now, five?
( Laughs )
I've lost count.
The Lord Commander asks that we
send more men to man the Wall.
Perhaps he's forgotten
we're fighting a war.
We have no men to spare.
"The cold winds
are rising
and the dead rise
with them."
The northerners are
a superstitious people.
According to the Commander,
one of these dead men
attacked him
in his chambers.
Mormont doesn't lie.
Varys: How do you kill
a dead man?
Apparently you burn him.
One trip to the Wall
and you come back
believing in grumpkins
and snarks.
I don't know
what I believe,
but here's
a fact for you--
the Night's Watch
is the only thing
that separates us from
what lies beyond the Wall.
I have every confidence
that the brave men
of the Night's Watch
will protect us all.
Dolorous Edd:
And I said,
"if the Gods wanted us
to have dignity,
they wouldn't make us
fart when we died."
Grenn:
We fart when we die?
Dolorous Edd:
My blessed mother--
I was holding her hand
when she left this world.
She farted so hard,
the whole bed shook.
( Blowing raspberry )
Seems a bit greedy for one man
to have so many wives.
Wouldn't two or three
be enough for him?
We were having
a serious discussion.
Would you look at that?
Nothing like the sight
of a woman walking away.
I prefer watching them
come towards me.
I'm sure
that's nice, too.
Yeah, well, there was
a milkmaid named Violet
on the next farm over
from where I grew up.
We were wrestling together
from the time we were six years old.
And then we got older
and the wrestling, uh...
Changed.
Sam:
You were with her?
How many times?
Well, as many times
as I could.
I wish I grew up
on a farm.
We need more potatoes.
Get another sack
from the sledge.
Get the turnips, too.
( Dog barking )
( Woman screams )
No. Ghost, no.
No!
Ghost, away.
Shoo, shoo!
You all right?
- Did he frighten you?
- You-- you shouldn't touch me.
Oh. Oh, right.
I'm sorry.
I just wanted to make sure
you weren't hurt.
You're very brave.
What are you doing?
This is Gilly.
She's one of Craster's...
daughters.
Hello, Gilly.
What are you doing?
Sam said
you could help.
I'm sorry, but Sam knows
we're not supposed--
She's pregnant.
Have to take her
with us when we leave.
What?
- What would that--
- Sam: I know it sounds a bit mad.
No, it doesn't sound a bit mad,
it's impossible.
- The Lord Commander ordered us to--
- We are sworn to protect.
- Sam, we can't take--
- please, ser, please.
I can still run
if I have to.
- It's just not possible.
- I'm going to have a baby.
If it's a boy...
If it's a boy, what?
You want us to risk
our lives for you
and you won't even
tell us why?
- Why'd you do that?
- Do what? Ask her a question?
- You were cruel.
- Cruel?
Sam, are you in such a hurry
to lose a hand?
- I didn't touch her.
- No, you just want to steal her.
What do you think
Craster cuts off for that?
I can't steal her.
She's a person,
not a goat.
We're heading deeper and deeper
into wildling territory.
We can't take a girl with us.
Mormont wouldn't have it.
And even if he would,
what would we do with her?
Who's going to
deliver a baby, you?
I could try.
What?
I've read about it.
A bit.
I'm sorry, Sam.
We can't help her.
( Sighs )
( Insects chittering,
buzzing )
( Sighs )
( Hoofbeats approaching )
- Khaleesi.
- ( Horse neighs )
( Breathing heavily )
( Flies buzzing )
- You don't need to see this.
- He is blood of my blood.
- Who did this?
- Khal Pono, perhaps.
Khal Jhaqo.
They don't like the idea of a woman
leading a Khalasar.
They will like it far less
when I am done with them.
( Weeping )
( Speaking Dothraki )
( Sobbing )
( Irri wailing )
( Seagulls screeching )
Is it as you remember,
My Lord?
It looks smaller.
Everything looks bigger
when you're a child.
I remember
my father's cabin
felt like a palace
when I was little.
Now look at it.
( Giggles )
They'll be waiting
for me on the docks.
Who will?
Anyone who matters.
This is a big day for them.
They haven't had much to get
excited about since I left.
It's a hard place,
the Iron Islands.
Always has been.
It's cold and it's wet.
Oh, I love
the cold and wet.
They say hard places
breed hard men.
And hard men
rule the world.
Then you'll be king
before long.
Try smiling with
your lips closed.
Better.
My father doesn't trust
you Iron islanders.
I don't blame him.
He says that you're all
reavers and rapers
and that no matter
how many women you have,
- you'll never be sat-- uh!
- ( Grunts )
- Quit talking about your father.
- ( Moans )
But he's right
about us.
Our wives from the Iron Islands,
they're for breeding.
That's not enough for us.
That's why
we take salt wives--
the women we capture.
Capture me.
Take me with you
when you go ashore.
- Make me your salt wife.
- Your place is on this ship.
Not after you leave.
Father will punish me.
He'll call me a whore.
I haven't paid you.
( Both grunting )
( Moaning )
Oh, yeah.
( Jewelry jangling )
( Door opens )
- Man: I paid good money...
- ( Door slams )
( Man grumbling )
- I'm not going to stand for this.
- ( Woman crying )
I barely touched her.
Now, you charge twice as much
as every other brothel
and this is
what I get-- crying.
One moment, my friend.
A moment.
( Snaps fingers )
Please accept
my sincerest apologies.
Aremca will take
good care of you.
( Crying continues )
- I'm sorry, My Lord.
- Shh, shh.
Did he hurt you?
No, My Lord.
( Sniffles )
It's Mhaegen.
Who?
She works for you.
She's the one--
the Gold Cloaks,
- they killed her baby.
- Ah, yes.
That was...
poorly handled.
Sometimes those
with the most power
have the least grace.
I can't stop
thinking about it.
I can't sleep.
That poor little baby.
You know, you remind me
of another girl,
a lovely thing
I once acquired
from a Lysene
pleasure house--
beautiful, like yourself,
and intelligent,
like yourself.
But she wasn't happy.
She cried often.
I asked her why,
but we didn't have
the kind of rapport
that you and I have.
Yes, it was quite sad.
Girls from the Lysene
pleasure houses are expensive,
extremely expensive.
And this one wasn't
making me any money.
I hate bad investments.
Really, I-- I do.
They haunt me.
I had no idea
how to make her happy,
no idea how
to mitigate my losses.
A very wealthy patron,
he offered me
a tremendous
amount of money
to let him transform
this lovely, sad girl.
To use her
in ways that...
Would never occur
to most men.
And you know what
occurs to most men.
I would not say he succeeded in
making her happy,
but my losses were
definitely mitigated.
Take tonight off
to mourn Mhaegen's child.
I'll see you tomorrow.
And you'll be happy?
That makes me happy.
- ( Distant hoofbeats )
- ( People chattering )
( Crying )
Tyrion:
More wine?
- Janos: Damn it, boy!
- Apologies, My Lord.
Leave us, Podrick. I believe we
know how to pour our own wine.
That's your new squire?
I could've found you
a proper lad.
Myself, I prefer
the improper ones.
Mm, that's a good red.
Dornish?
You know your wines,
My Lord.
That I do.
( Sighs )
A fine dinner, My Lord.
Call me Tyrion, please.
I'm sure you're getting
used to fine dinners,
now that you're a lord.
Maybe I'll hire
this cook of yours.
Wars have been
started for less.
( Both laugh )
I heard there was some trouble in
Littlefinger's brothel the other night.
Mm, nasty business.
- Had to be done.
- Yes, of course.
The City Watch
must keep the peace,
only I hadn't realized
peace depended on killing babies.
- Orders are orders.
- Quite right.
Especially
the queen's orders.
I never said they were
No, but who else would want to
murder King Robert's bastards?
She's always been
a jealous woman.
You know your sister
better than I do.
You've heard the awful rumors
about my brother and sister?
I don't listen to filth.
That's good of you,
but you have heard them.
I suppose people who do believe
that filth consider Robert's bastards
to be better claimants to the throne
than Cersei's children.
Joffrey is my king.
The rest doesn't interest me.
I appreciate
your loyalty.
Tell me, when your men
slaughtered Ned Stark's men
in the throne room,
did you give the order?
I did.
And I would again.
The man was a traitor.
He tried to buy
my loyalty.
The fool.
He had no idea
you were already bought.
Are you drunk?
I'll not have my honor
questioned by an Imp!
I'm not questioning
Your Honor, Lord Janos.
I'm denying its existence.
If you think I'll stand here
and take this from you, dwarf--
Dwarf? Mm, you should
have stopped at Imp.
And, yes, you will stand here
and take it from me,
unless you'd like to take it
from my friend here.
I intend to serve
as Hand of the King
until my father
returns from the war.
And seeing as you betrayed
the last Hand of the King,
well, I just wouldn't
feel safe with you lurking about.
What are you t--
my friends at court
will not allow this!
- The queen herself has granted--
- The queen regent.
And you're a fool to believe
she is your friend.
We shall hear what Joffrey
has to say about this.
- No, we shan't.
- ( Footsteps approach )
( Doors open )
There's a ship leaving
for Eastwatch-by-the-Sea tonight.
From there I'm afraid it's rather
a long walk to Castle Black.
I hope you enjoy the Wall.
I found it
surprisingly beautiful...
In a brutal, horribly
uncomfortable sort of way.
The lads will escort you.
The streets aren't safe
at night, My Lord.
These men are
under my command!
I command you to arrest
this cutthroat.
His name is Bronn
and he is the new
commander of the City Watch.
Boys.
( Janos grunting )
I have friends at court,
powerful friends!
The king himself
made me a lord!
To the new Commander.
If I told you to murder
an infant girl, say,
still at her
mother's breast,
would you do it
without question?
Without question? No.
I'd ask, "how much?"
( Chatter )
( Horse neighs )
If they come back,
I say we yield.
Gendry's the one
they want.
Don't want to get caught
in the middle of a battle.
I ain't afraid
of no battles.
If you got within a mile of a battle,
you'd fill your pants.
I've seen
lots of battles.
- I saw--
- Liar.
I saw a man
kill another man
just outside a tavern
in Flea Bottom.
Stabbed him
right in the neck.
Two men fighting
isn't a battle.
- They had armor on.
- So?
So, if they've got armor on,
it's a battle.
No, it isn't.
What does a dyer's apprentice
know about battles anyway?
Gendry's an armorer's
apprentice.
Hot pie, tell Gendry
what makes a fight into a battle.
It's, um, when
they've got armor on.
Gendry:
Who told you that?
A knight.
How'd you know
he was a knight?
Well, it was 'cause
he got armor on.
You don't have to be a knight
to have armor.
Any idiot
can buy armor.
Hot pie:
How do you know?
'Cause I sold armor.
What do the Gold Cloaks
want with you?
- No idea.
- You're a liar.
You know, you shouldn't insult
people that are bigger than you.
Then I wouldn't get
to insult anyone.
I don't care
what any of them want.
No good's ever come
of their questions.
No good's ever come?
Who asked questions
before?
How can someone so small be such
a huge pain in my ass?
Who asked questions?
The Hand of the King.
Hands of the King.
Lord Arryn came first
a few weeks before he died,
and then Lord Stark came
a few weeks before he died.
Lord Stark?
See? Asking me
questions is bad luck.
You'll probably
be dead soon.
- What did they ask about?
- My mom.
- Who's your mom?
- Just my mom--
worked in a tavern,
died when I was little.
And who was your father?
Could've been one of those
gold-hatted bastards, for all I know.
What about you anyway?
You thought
they were after you.
Why?
Did you kill someone or is it
just because you're a girl?
- I'm not a girl.
- Yes, you are.
Do you think I'm as stupid
as the rest of them?
Stupider.
The Night's Watch doesn't take girls,
everyone knows that.
Yeah, that's true,
but you're still a girl.
I am not!
Yeah? Well, pull your cock out
and take a piss, then.
I don't need
to take a piss.
Lommy and hot pie
can't know.
No one can know.
Well, they won't,
not from me.
My name's not Arry.
It's Arya...
of House Stark.
Yoren is taking me home
to Winterfell.
He was your father--
the Hand, the traitor.
He was never a traitor.
Joffrey is a liar.
So you're a highborn, then.
You're a lady.
No. I mean, yes.
My mother was a lady
and my sister--
Yeah, but you were
a lord's daughter
and you lived
in a castle and you--
look, all that about cocks,
I should never have said--
and I've been pissing
in front of you and everything.
I-- I should be
calling you "My Lady."
- Do not call me "My Lady."
- As My Lady commands.
Well, that was unladylike.
Oh!
( Laughs )
( Seagulls screeching )
( Chatter )
( Hammers banging )
What's she carrying?
Myrish oranges,
wine from the Arbor...
And the heir to Pyke
and the Iron Islands.
The only living son
of Balon Greyjoy.
Me.
I don't like wine.
Woman's drink.
I need to get to Pyke.
I'll find you a horse.
I'm heading that way.
I can take you there.
I bet you can.
Have you been
at sea long?
Or were there just no women
where you came from?
- None like you.
- You don't know what I'm like.
Maybe you don't know
what you're like.
Maybe you need
someone to teach you.
Do you know who I am?
You think I offer free rides
to every man in jewelry,
Lord Greyjoy?
Have my things sent up
to the castle.
You should give me
the reins.
I'm a better rider
than you.
I've been on horseback
for the past nine years.
Nine years?
Do you still know
your way around a ship?
Have these hands
ever touched a rope?
Don't you worry
about my hands.
The sea is in my blood.
Your blood will be in the sea
if I don't watch where I'm going.
I have a proposal
for my father,
one that will
make him king again,
and me after him.
You may get to stay
in a castle tonight if you're lucky.
Is that an offer
from my future king?
An order from
your future king.
You can tell your grandchildren
about this night.
Woman: I don't imagine it will be
a story fit for children.
( Footsteps approaching )
Theon: Father.
Nine years, is it?
They took
a frightened boy.
What have
they given back?
A man.
- Your blood and your heir.
- We shall see.
Stark had you
longer than I did.
Lord Stark is gone.
And how do you feel
about that?
What's done is done.
I've brought you
a proposal from Robb Stark.
Who gave you
those clothes?
Was it Ned Stark's pleasure
to make you his daughter?
If my clothes offend you,
I will change them.
You will.
That bauble
'round your neck--
did you pay the iron price
for it or the gold?
I asked a question.
Did you pull it from the neck
of a corpse you made
or did you buy it
to match your fine clothes?
Iron or gold?
Gold.
I'll not have my son
dressed as a whore.
( Necklace clinks )
My fears have come true--
the Starks
have made you theirs.
- My blood is salt and iron.
- Yet the Stark boy sends you to me
like a trained raven
clutching his message.
The offer he makes
is one I proposed.
- He heeds your counsel?
- I've lived with him,
hunted with him,
fought at his side.
He thinks of me
as a brother.
No, not here,
not in my hearing.
You will not
name him brother,
this son of the man who put
your true brothers to the sword.
Or have you forgotten
your own blood?
I forget nothing.
I remember my brothers.
And I remember
when my father was a king.
I see.
I destroy Robb Stark's
enemies for him
and he will make me
king of the Iron Islands once again.
- I will lead the attack myself.
- Oh, you will?
I'm your son,
your only living heir.
- Who else?
- ( Door opens )
I told you to wait outside.
How did you get
past the guards?
Anything with a cock
is easy to fool.
My dear.
Yara?
So good to see you,
brother.
This is a homecoming I'll tell
my grandchildren about.
She can't lead an attack!
- Balon: And why not?
- You're a woman!
- You're the one in skirts.
- This isn't Winterfell, boy.
Your sister took over command
of your eldest brother's ship
after your new father
killed him.
All:
What's dead may never die.
The only nights she's spent
off these islands
have been spent
on the sea.
She's commanded men.
She's killed men.
She knows who she is.
No man gives me
a crown.
I pay the iron price.
I will take my crown,
for that is who I am.
That is who
we have always been.
You won't stand a chance against
the Lannisters on your own.
Who said anything
about the Lannisters?
Davos:
You'll have your gold
when we take the treasury
at King's Landing.
Salladhor: All these kings
fighting for the throne,
and this Stannis
has the smallest army.
Why would I bet on the man
with the worst chance?
Because you're
a smart gambler.
Stannis has proved
himself in war twice.
His baby brother has never set foot
on a battlefield.
Neither has
the false King Joffrey.
And yet they both
have larger armies.
Stannis has just
begun the fight.
His Bannermen
will rally to his cause.
There's no man
in the Seven Kingdoms
more honorable
than Stannis Baratheon
or more worthy
of loyalty.
What is the world
coming to
when smugglers must vouch
for the honor of kings?
- Mind your words, pirate.
- Matthos.
You think I'm insulted?
I am a pirate.
I'm an excellent pirate.
I don't sail
for promises.
Of course you do.
Every time you leave harbor,
you're leaving on a promise--
a promise that
somewhere on the sea,
somebody's got some gold
and you can take it from him.
- That's a promise that always comes true.
- As is mine.
You're not a young man,
Salladhor.
And correct me
if I'm wrong--
most pirates
don't grow old.
Only the clever ones.
You want to spend
your last few years on the sea
stealing from
Pentoshi cheesemongers
and Meereenese
silk merchants?
Then go.
They're out there waiting for you.
That's easy.
What I'm offering you
is hard.
Come with me and plunder
the greatest city in Westeros.
You'll be the richest man
in Lys and the most famous.
They'll be singing songs about you
as long as men have voices to sing.
"Salladhor Saan"
is a good name for songs.
- It is.
- One thing-- I want the queen.
- The queen?
- Cersei-- I want her.
I'll sail with your fleet,
all 30 of my ships.
And if we don't drown at the bottom
of Blackwater Bay,
I will fuck this blonde queen
and I'll fuck her well.
This war
isn't about you.
We're not attacking King's Landing
so that you can rape the queen.
I'm not going to rape her.
I'm going to fuck her.
As if she would
just let you.
You don't know
how persuasive I am.
I've never tried
to fuck you.
Stannis is the rightful king
and the Lord of Light,
- the one true God--
- ( Groans )
I've been all over
the world, my boy,
and everywhere I go,
people tell me about the true Gods.
They all think
they found the right one.
The one true God
is what's between a woman's legs,
and better yet,
a queen's legs.
I never thought you'd have
a true believer for a son.
Eh, he's young yet.
I promise you the gold.
I promise you the glory.
I cannot promise you
the queen.
You believe
your king can win?
He is the one true king.
You Westerosi
are funny people.
A man chops off your fingers
and you fall in love with him.
( Laughs )
I'll sail with you,
Davos Seaworth.
You're the most honest
smuggler I ever met.
Make me rich.
Get me to the gates
of King's Landing and I will.
Matthos: When will the king
have us sail?
As soon as his God
wills it.
He's my God, too,
and yours,
but you are
too blind to see.
- Let me teach you how to read.
- Oh, you and your mother.
It won't take long.
You already know the letters.
The holy books are much more
persuasive than I can be.
I wish I had
a God, truly.
I'm not mocking you, but I've seen
men pray to every God there is--
pray for wind, pray for rain,
pray for home.
- None of it works.
- But you always came home.
- I wasn't praying.
- No, but I was.
Every night
that you were at sea,
I lit a candle
and I prayed for you.
You want me
to have a God?
Fine. King Stannis
is my God.
He raised me up
and blessed me with his trust.
He gave you a future
I could never have imagined.
You know how to read.
You'll be a knight someday.
You think a fire God
commanded all that?
It was Stannis,
only Stannis.
Stannis is my king,
but he's only a man.
Don't tell him that.
( Laughs )
Cersei: Lord Janos Slynt was
commander of the City Watch.
You had no right
to exile him.
I have every right.
I am the King's Hand.
You're serving as the King's Hand
till father gets here.
I am Queen Regent.
Listen to me,
Queen Regent.
You're losing the people.
- Do you hear me?
- ( Laughs ) The people.
You think I care?
You might
find it difficult
to rule over millions
who want you dead.
Half the city will starve
when winter comes.
The other half will plot
to overthrow you.
And your gold-plated thugs
just gave them
their rallying cry--
"The Queen
slaughters babies."
You don't even have
the decency to deny it.
It wasn't you who gave
the order, was it?
Joffrey didn't
even tell you.
Did he tell you?
I imagine that
would be even worse.
He did what needed
to be done.
You want to be Hand of the King?
You want to rule?
This is what ruling is--
lying on a bed of weeds,
ripping them out
by the root, one by one,
before they strangle you
in your sleep.
I'm no king, but I think there's more
to ruling than that.
I don't care
what you think!
You've never
taken it seriously.
You haven't,
Jaime hasn't.
It's all fallen on me.
As has Jaime repeatedly,
according to Stannis Baratheon.
You're funny.
You've always
been funny...
But none of your jokes
will ever match
the first one, will they?
You remember?
Back when you ripped
my mother open
on your way out of her
and she bled to death?
She was my mother, too.
Mother gone...
For the sake of you.
There's no bigger joke
in the world than that.
( Waves crashing,
seagulls screeching )
( Door opens )
- Your Grace.
Stannis: How did you fare
with your pirate?
Salladhor Saan will join
our fleet-- 30 ships.
His men know
how to fight.
In my experience, pirates
prefer fighting unarmed men.
It does seem
the wiser choice.
There won't be
a choice this time.
Do you trust him?
Salladhor Saan
is an old friend.
I've known him 30 years.
I've never trusted him,
but once he gets the smell of gold,
he never stops.
Well, if he does his job,
he'll have his share.
Leave us.
At once, Your Grace.
The Lord of Light shines
through you, young warrior.
( Whispering )
Come.
( Doors close )
What did you say to him?
I told him death by fire
is the purest death.
- Why?
- Because it is true.
You're troubled, my king.
Yeah.
These armies are toys
for the Lord of Light.
Tell your lord
to burn them, then.
I tell him nothing.
I pray for his commands
and I obey.
My little brother has 100,000
men according to the scouts,
men whose allegiance
rightly belongs to me.
You must have faith.
Faith?
In a real war, the side
with the greater number wins
nine times out of 10.
Then we must be
the 10th.
I cannot defeat
my brother in the field.
And I can't take King's Landing
without the men he's stolen.
I have seen the path
to victory in the flames.
But first, you must give yourself
to the Lord of Light.
I've said the words,
damn you.
I burnt the idols.
You must give
all of yourself.
I have a wife.
I took a vow.
She's sickly, weak...
Shut away in a tower.
She disgusts you.
And she's given
you nothing--
no sons,
only stillborns,
only death.
I will give you
a son, my king.
A son?
( Gasps )
( Grunting )
( Wind howling )
( Footsteps )
( Baby cooing )
( Bird warbling )
- ( Bird screeching, wings flapping )
- ( Crow caws )
( Scraping, jangling )
( Rustling )
- ( Wood scraping )
- ( Twigs snapping )
- ( Snarls )
- ( Gasps )
- ( Clicking )
- ( Baby crying )
( Creature chittering )
( Creature snarling )
( Baby continues crying )
( Crying )
( Guttural clicking )
( Gasps )
( Theme music playing )
== sync, corrected by elderman ==